# Omar Oualha Software Engineering

Highly seasoned and dedicated IT Professional with all-round technical expertise & an exceptional record of client satisfaction. Adept at facilitating clear and transparent communication between all levels of company staff. Able to work well independently or in coordination with a team. Extensive practical knowledge of complex systems' hardware, software & network.



## Personal Details

St 08 Rafeha City, Nr 22 2098 Tunis, Tunisia Email: oualhaomar@gmail.com Phone number: (+216) 27 170 090



# **Professional Experience**

#### Esprit-Electrify Network | Tunisia.

Aug. 2018 - Present

#### MEVN STACK

> SUCCESS STORY:

Conception and development of a platform destined for people to participate in an online presidential or parliamentary election or different other types of vote in order to revolutionize the way we vote using the Blockchain technology.

#### Tools - Code used:

• UML, Scrum, Mongo DB, Express JS, Vue JS, Node JS, Blockchain, GIT.

Coin FM | Poland

Apr. 2018 - June 2018

#### Web developer (Freelance)

Crypto Currency registered & licensed exchange startup platform under CFM holdings, Talinn, Estonia; www.coin.fm

> SUCCESS STORY: 1st crypto emerging technology project

Developing a Crypto exchange website, with API integrations.

#### Tools – Code used:

· PHP, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Python, AJAX, Laravel.

#### OOREDOO | Tunisia

Jan. 2018- Mar. 2018

#### System and Networks Administrator

- > SUCCESS STORY:
  - •Routing Protocols RIP EIGRP OSPF BGP MPLS VRF.
  - •Configuration DNS, Active Directory, IDS, OpenVPN.
  - •Installation and management of backup tools.
  - Configuration and maintenance of Pfsense Firewalls.

**RESULTS** - The establishment of the whole Networking infrastructure.

#### Tools - Code used:

 Windows Server, Exchange, Vmware, ZABBIX monitoring, Apache, FTP, FileZilla, ZIMBRA(mail), MongoDB, GNS3, LINUX.

#### Esprit | Tunisia

Sep. 2017 - Dec. 2017

#### DEVELOPMENT AND INTEGRATION PROJECT (ACADEMIC PROJECT)

#### SUCCESS STORY:

I was involved in all aspects of development, creating a website, mobile application, after the conception of the database for the management of claims and insurance.

#### Tools – Code used:

 Java, JavaEE, Spring, SpringBoot, Maven, XHTML, .NET, ASP, Visual Studio, Microsoft Sql server, Android, Android Studio, API REST, Restful web services

#### Freelance | Tunisia.

June. 2017 - Aug. 2017

#### WEB DEVELOPER (FREELANCE)

> SUCCESS STORY: 5-Star forum integration

Conception and development of a Multi-services Forum where you can get the latest news about movies, TV Series and Games. The forum is developed as a web application. We used different technologies for the development of the back end and front end of the application.

#### Tools - Code used:

· Symfony3, Angular4, MySQL, VisualCode, PHPStorm, Mamp, API REST, Restful web services.

Esprit | Tunisia. Jan. 2017 - May. 2017

#### E-COMMERCE WEB APPLICATION

#### SUCCESS STORY:

conception and development of a multiplatform Deals shop. The deals allow people to get the best deals In Tunisia, to get discounts on a variety of goods such as food, clothes, restaurants, cosmetics...

Desktop: Developing an Office Application based on APIs and using the JavaFx graphical library.

Web: Creating a web application with the Symfony3 Framework and integration of an array of external bundles (Friends of symfony User(FOS), BBcode ...).

Mobile: Creating a Mobile App with the Code Name One Framework and integration of external services (websocket).

#### Tools - Code used:

UML, Java8, JavaFX, Symfony3, twig, HTML, CSS, Java Script, Ajax, JQuerry, CodeName One, SQL, JSON, XML

Esprit | Tunisia.

Jan. 2016 - May. 2016

#### WEB APPLICATION DEVELOPER (GRADUATION PROJECT)

Leading company in computer engineering and web service, offering Offshore services in web development & web marketing.

SUCCESS STORY: Outstanding Support Delivery

Developed a cognitive web application for health & lifestyle. Manage doctors and patients appointments.

**Results** - Achieved key goals within time constraints and 18% under revised budget.

#### Tools - Code used:

UML | PHP5 | SQL | HTML5 | CSS3 | Agil Methodologie | Scrum | Design | Adobe Photoshop | Adobe Illustrator



### Education

#### Private High Institute of Engineering and Technology ESPRIT.

Sep. 2016 - Present

- Field: Software Engineering, ENGINEERING CURRICULUM
- Result: Extensive Achievement A+ in the 1st grade

#### The Higher institute of Multimedia Arts "ISAMM" | Tunisia

Sep. 2013 - May. 2016

- Field: Computing and Multimedia (Computer Science), Bachelor Degree
- Result: Honors: on top of the institution grades



# Volunteering / Internships

#### Summer Camp, Ukraine

Jun. 2015 - Aug. 2015

#### Web Development summer internship

#### DUTIES:

· Designing and implementing a website to manage children's camps holiday requests.

### Tools - Code used:

UML, PHP, Wordpress, SQL.

#### AIESEC, MEDINA office

2014 - 2016

#### The Vice President in charge Marketing and Communication

- •Planning within the Executive Board the projects of the next mandate.
- Manage the team on internal and external communication
- Manage teams to achieve event success.
- Train Members on Marketing Plan.
- Prepare reports of the activity
   Team building to motivate the team
- Search for sponsors

#### Certifications | AWARDS

2017-2018

- · Cisco Networking Academy Entrepreneurship
- CCNAroutingandswitching



# Languages

Arabic : Native
French : Fluent (C1)
English : Well(B2)

German.: Beginner(Certification A1)



# Key Skills

Detail-oriented, Organized, Creative, Problem Solver, Diplomatic Genuinely



# **Technical Skills**

Development Platforms: JAVA | JAVA EE | ASP| .NET | SHAREPOINT | Maven | spring | Rest | Restfull

**Programming:** C | Java | SQL | JSP | C# | Script Shell | jsf

 $\textbf{Web:} \ HTML \ | \ PHP \ | \ CSS \ | \ Ajax \ | \ JQuery \ | \ Javascript \ | \ Angular \ | \ Node.js \ | \ Vue \ JS \ | \ React \ | \ Rubby \ | \ Symfony \ | \ Laravellar \ | \ Laravellar$ 

CMS: drupal | wordpress

 $\textbf{DataBases:} \ \ SQL \ | \ PLSQL \ | \ NoSQL \ | \ ORACLE \ | \ Microsoft \ Sql \ server.$ 

Environments: Linux | Windows | Ubuntu | Debian | OS X. Modelization: UML | Scrum | Agil

IDE and Software: Adobe PhotoShop | Adobe Illustrator | NetBeans | Eclipse | Apache | Tomcat | PHPStorm | VisualStudio | GIT |

Sublime Text | Talend | Jboss | Rstudio | Python | Microsoft SQL Server.